新浪微博 @摆渡字幕组 发布
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
翻译：Emma Watson/key/呵呵/Margaret
翻译：enchanted/张天烊/不酸的柠檬/初夏晚夏
校对：JayJayLiu
摆渡字幕组翻译/APP开发志愿者招募中 报名群:377256405
“但你如果作恶 就该惧怕
"But if you do wrong, be afraid,
因为他佩带刀剑就是为了惩恶扬善
for he does not bear the sword in vain.
他是神的仆役
He is the servant of God,
是降临震怒到作恶人身上
an avenger who carries out God's wrath
的报应者“
on the wrongful."
每当我读到圣经《罗马书》13:4时
I often thought of my friend
我总会想起我的朋友
Officer Reginald Dean Davis,
雷金纳德 · 迪安 · 戴维斯警官
when I would read Romans 13:4.
在他被残忍杀害之前
That he punished two of the three men who attacked him
他惩罚了袭击他的三个人中的两个
before he himself was killed
正因如此 每当我吟诵这一段圣经时
means I will never think of anyone else ever again
这经文只属于他一个人
when I read or speak this verse.
他为保护家人而死
He died protecting his family,
为保护朋友 保护这座城市而牺牲
his friends and this city.
他曾是神的仆役
He was a servant of God.
我常通过一些事来安慰自己
I assuage my rage that a third man escaped
以缓解我对逃脱的第三者的愤怒
by trying to remind myself of a few things.
首先
First,
雷金纳德找到了一位
Reginald found a woman
和她一样坚强 进取 机敏的妻子
as strong, driven and smart as he.
其次 是他的儿子
And then I think of his boy,
安德烈
Andre,
从他身上我看到了和他父亲一样的品质
and I see the same, sometimes infuriating,
无畏无惧
fearlessness,
求知若渴
inquisitiveness.
我知道你现在不这么想
I know it may not feel like it now,
但 安德烈 这十三年你从你父亲身上学到的
but you got more from your father, Andre, in 13 years
比大多数男人穷尽一生学到的都多
than most men will in a lifetime.
他教会你遵循自己良知
He taught you to follow your conscience,
不以人云亦云来判断对错
to not take anyone else's word about what is right and wrong,
在这个残酷的世界里
to find a just code
找寻到公平与正义
in an often cruel world.
十九年后
感谢你在下班时抽出时间来内务局
Thank you for making time for IA at the end of your shift.
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice.
你可以选择不当警察
You could choose not to be a cop.
当警察这件事不是我能决定的
Being a cop isn't a choice for me.
那是什么决定的？
What is it, then?
基因
DNA.
事到如今 我觉得我们没必要解释
At this point, we don't need to spell out
为什么我们都在这儿
why we're all here.
不 得解释 这是官方程序
Yes, we do. Official procedure.
任何警官在执行任务使用武器时
Any officer who discharges his or her weapon in the line of duty
都必须证明每一次开火都是恰当合理的
must justify every round of ammunition.
你九年杀了八个人
You've shot eight people in nine years.
是 枪法精准 一人不留
Good shootings. Cleared on all.
你当上警探以来杀了三个
Three since you were made detective.
现在有四个了
Four now.
那个幸存的被判处终身监禁不得释放
The one who survived was sentenced to life without.
你有对任何一个后悔过吗
Do you regret any?
我看过心理医生了
I've been to the psychologist.
你没有回答我的问题
That's not an answer.
不 我一点也不后悔
No, I do not regret any.
你睡觉时不会梦见他们的脸吗？
Faces don't come to you in your sleep?
正义是需要代价的
Justice comes at a cost.
正义与否不是由你来裁决的
Justice is not determined by you.
但我就在那裁决的最前线
But I am the sharp end of that determination.
谁告诉你的？
Says who?
我的警徽
My badge.
我入职时的宣誓
My oath.
还有你的基因？
Your DNA?
南北战争的时候
During the Civil War,
一些士兵只是在不停给步枪上膛 却未曾开过火
some soldiers just kept loading their muskets without ever firing.
一次装了五六发枪弹
Five or six balls loaded on top of each other.
越南战争时 只有百分之三十的前线步兵开过枪
In Vietnam, only 30% of frontline infantry soldiers ever fired a shot.
也就是说 打仗时十个士兵里只有三个真正在战斗
So, ten soldiers in battle, only three truly fighting.
你真的想要用战争来类比吗 警探戴维斯？
Are you really using war analogies here, Detective Davis?
你以为另外七个在干什么？
What do you imagine the other seven were doing?
嘿 安德烈你来了
Hi, Andre.
她情况如何？
How's she doing?
很疲劳 不过我给她喂过药了
Tired, but I just gave her her meds.
好的 你可以回家了 这里交给我吧
All right, you can head home. I got this.
好的
Okay.
如果你需要我 你知道怎么找我
You know where to find me if you need me.
在看什么呢？
What are we watching?
你丢下了我
You left me.
不是 妈妈 我有一堆忙事儿
No, Ma. I had to pull a triple.
我在这里呆太久了
I've been here too long.
我……
I've...
我是不是在这儿呆太久了
I've overstayed my welcome.
不 你想呆多久就呆多久
Nah. You can never overstay your welcome.
你是来带我回家的吗？
You're here to take me home？
你现在就在家里
This is home.
别把我丢在这儿 雷吉纳德
Don't leave me here, Reginald.
妈妈……
Ma...
是我 安德烈
it's Andre.
妈妈 是我 是小安
It's Dre, Mama.
我得吃药了
I need to take my meds.
不不不 你吃过了
No, no, no. You took them.
你已经吃过了
You already took them.
你看起来很疲惫
You look tired.
你工作太辛苦了
You work too hard.
这点你倒是说的没错
Yeah, you got that right.
工作嘛
It's the job.
你知道我干什么的
It's what I do.
我知道
I know.
你要勇于去直视恶魔
You gotta look the devil in the eye.
好
Yeah.
好的 妈妈
Yeah, Ma.
这里看起来跟你描述的别无二致
Well, it looks just like you said it would.
那个 你的面罩闻起来像你胡子吗？
Hey, does yours smell like your beard?
不 像你的马子
It smells like your girl.
出发吧
Let's go.
你们是什么人
Who the fuck are you guys?
我们是来取你可卡因的
We're the guys that are taking your cocaine.
傻得够呛 你们是来送死的
Not smart. You guys are gonna fucking die.
那玩意在哪儿？
Where is it?
冷藏室 在楼下
Freezer. Downstairs.
要钥匙吗？
We need a key?
来的就你们俩？
Just two of you?
今晚你们走不了了
You're gonna be here all night.
喂！
Yo!
走！
Move!
这可不是三十公斤
That's not 30 keys.
是三百公斤
It's 300.
看来有人出了岔子
Somebody fucked up.
闭嘴 跪下
Shut up. On your knees.
天呐
Jeez.
这玩意儿是纯的
This stuff hasn't been cut yet.
哦吼！我们中头奖了！
Jackpot! Fuck yeah!
没门 我们走
No way. We walk.
-什么？ -我们走
- What? - We walk.
你年龄小也有不机灵的时候
Small ain't always smart.
你要么来搭把手 要么一边看着
You can help or you can watch.
这真是蠢到家了
This is fucking stupid.
这就是自由
This is fucking freedom.
妈的
Shit.
嘘
Shh.
这家伙在哪儿？
The fuck is this guy at?
可能在后门那边 去看看
He might be by the back door. Check it out.
后边儿的车还没熄火
Car back here is still running.
后门是开着的
Back gate open.
可能在进行毒品交易
Possible 30 in progress.
干 行吧 我们进来了
Shit. All right. We're coming in.
呆在后面！
Stay back.
交火 这里有交火！有警员中枪了！
Shots fired! Shots fired! Officer down!
有人开火 重复 有人开火
Shots fired! Shots fired!
有警员倒了！
Officer down!
那个条子 你走！
Cop! Run!
我们不想再看到有人死了
We don't want any more blood!
你可以不用杀他的
You don't have to kill him.
有更多人来了
More are coming.
开车
Drive.
掩护我
Cover me.
把车挪开
Move the car.
8-5队亚当
8-5 Adam.
8-5队查理
8-5 Charlie.
8-5队查理 听得见吗？
8-5 Charlie, on the air?
8-5队富兰克？
8-5 Frank?
任何在莫斯托的警员 收到请回答
Any units at Mosto's, please reply.
红灯快停车
Stop for this light.
-你在干什么 我说快停车  -我们刚干掉了几个警察
- What the fuck are you doing? I said stop. - We just fucking killed cops.
见鬼！
Fuck!
指挥中心 我们有数名警员中枪！
Central, we got multiple officers down!
需要急救 重复 需要急救
Put a rush on the bus. I repeat, put a rush on the bus!
控制中心 通知高速中心 血库
Central, notify highways, blood banks.
这里是亚当急救车 我们在中央大街 告诉我们路线
Emergency Adam. Main Central, show us en route.
警员中枪.
Officers down.
八名警员中枪.
Eight officers down.
麦肯纳队长
Captain McKenna.
好的 各位.
Okay, boys.
戴维斯探员.
Detective Davis.
麦肯纳队长负责8-5警队
Captain McKenna runs the 8-5.
今晚死的都是他的部下
These are his boys that died tonight.
节哀顺变.
My condolences.
谢谢
Thank you.
安德烈对吗？
It's Andre, right?
是的 长官.
Yes, sir.
我从没见过慈父 但我听过很多他的英勇事迹.
I never met your dad, but I heard good things.
谢谢 长官.
Thank you, sir.
伙计们 你们得起身离开
Guys, I need you to get up.
你们坐的地方是犯罪现场
You're sitting in my crime scene.
快点 别妨碍他办事
Come on. He's got a job to do.
没事的 凯利
It's okay, Kelly.
我听说你今天去了内务局
I heard you were with IA today.
如果你明天能回来我会很开心的
And I'd fucking love it if you were right back there tomorrow.
如果他们给我一个理由的话.
If they give me cause.
理由？
Cause?
这就是你该死的理由 可以吗？
Here's your fucking cause right there. Okay?
-明白我说的吗  -各位出去吧
- You understand what I'm saying? - Give me the room.
现在有七名警员横尸街头
Your fucking cause times seven lying dead in the fucking street.
这么多理由够了吗
Motherfuckers are giving you all the reason you need...
麦肯 你不是唯一难过的人
Mac! You're not the only one hurting here.
这里是公众场合
You're in public.
警员倒下时 公众什么都没看到.
The public who never sees shit when a cop goes down.
声音轻点
Lower your voice.
他们叫什么名字
What were their names?
嗯
Uh, yeah.
詹妮弗·蒙哥马利在救护车上.
Jennifer Montgomery in the ambulance.
她现在命悬一线
She's hanging on by a thread.
马西莫·亚当斯 查理·科布.
Massimo Adams, Charlie Cobb.
杰克·多明格斯和丹尼·威廉姆斯
Jake Dominguez and Danny Williams.
街上是马库斯·费尔南德斯.
Out on the street is Marcus Fernandez.
什么？
What?
马库斯·费尔南德斯.
Marcus Fernandez.
我认识马库斯.
I knew Marcus.
我们上的同一所大学.
We were at the academy together.
和马库斯一起的
Out there with Marcus...
是鲁本·基泽和帕特里克·格雷厄姆.
is Reuben Kizer and Patrick Graham.
如你所知
Just so you know,
他们留下了四个遗孀
they leave behind four wives,
一个未婚妻
one fiancée,
和六个孩子.
six kids.
其中三个还是我的教子.
Three are my godkids.
我现在不得不在半夜叫醒他们
Now I'm gonna go wake them up in the middle of the night,
告诉他们这个天塌般的噩耗
let them know their lives are shattered.
你知道演练吗
You know the drill.
告诉你
Look, I fucking refuse
我不会因为审判上诉
to allow these families to be traumatized even more
假释听证会和某些不着边际的陈述
with fucking trials and appeals and horseshit narratives,
让这些家庭遭受更多的创伤了
parole hearings for, fuck, three, four decades.
我在请求你
I'm asking you...
保护他们免遭这些事情的伤害
to protect them from that.
我明白.
I understand.
他们为什么在这儿？
Why were they here?
我的人刚防范了一宗抢劫案.
My guys interrupted a robbery.
这里有多少可卡因？
How much cocaine is this?
这些人渣给毒品提纯之前
Crime Scene estimates about 300 kilos
犯罪现场估计有300公斤可卡因.
before the scumbags cut into it.
他们拿走了多少？
How much did they take?
差不多50公斤
About 50 keys.
110磅.
One hundred and ten pounds.
那是A1的重量 你看的是25年的
That's A1 weight. You're looking at 25 years.
纯度超过九成.
Ninety-plus percent pure.
两百万左右 在你来之前
Two million, plus or minus, before you step on it.
之后是四倍
It's quadruple after.
安德烈·戴维斯警探 这位是弗兰基·伯恩斯 缉毒局的
Detective Andre Davis, Detective Frankie Burns, DETF.
-她将与你一起共事  -和我干嘛？
- She'll be working with you. - With me doing what?
这是我目前所知最大的一次检获
This is the biggest coke seizure in I don't know how long.
-将涉及毒品  -我很感激这项政策
- Narcotics will be involved. - I appreciate the politics.
未来3到4个小时如果我不能将这帮暴徒绳之于法 就再也抓不到了
But if I don't catch these guys in the next three or four hours, they vanish.
这不是政策
I don't do fucking politics.
她和我们是一队的
And she's not the second team.
你可以和我唱反调 也可以与我合作
You can either fight me or use me.
你还好吗？
You good?
我们该以死谢罪
We should fucking kill ourselves.
别那样 现在不是时候
Don't be like that. Not now.
雷 我们不知杀了多少个警察
We just killed more cops than I can fucking count, Ray.
都是我杀的
I did all the killing.
你认为他们不会在乎尸体数量吗？
You think they give a shit about the body math?
他们会发现我们的.
They're gonna figure us out.
天很黑 我们行动迅速 车子不是我们的 车牌也是偷来的
It was dark. We moved fast. Car's not ours. Plates are stolen.
迟早会败露的 雷 好吗
It'll get solved, Ray. All right?
我们都很讨厌条子 但不得不承认他们很聪明
We both hate the fucking cops, but they're smart.
天亮前他们就能查出我们 我们得赶紧跑路
They're gonna figure out our names by sunrise. We need to run.
我们得定个计划 我们需要钱
We need a plan. We need money.
该死！
Fuck!
这是员工？
Employee?
对的 从后方潜入
Yeah. Came up whistle-clean.
这个丧命的好市民叫汤姆·切弗
No-scroll good citizen named Tom Cheaver.
汤姆是近距离中弹的
So, Tom took his bullet from just a few feet.
注意伤口周围的点
Notice the stippling around the entrance wound.
从那把刀的位置判断
And judging from the proximity of that knife,
汤姆打算偷袭
Tom tried to make a move.
在这里
Over here,
两次击发
double taps.
自动式压制武器
Automatic weapon, suppressed.
我说有两个枪手
I say two shooters.
你怎么看出来的
Where are you seeing that?
一个人不可能轻松解决掉这么多警察
No one's smooth enough to murder all these officers
还要杀死拿刀偷袭的汤姆
and hit Tom coming up with a knife.
一个人也不可能独自携带100多磅的可卡因
And one guy probably isn't carrying 100-plus pounds of cocaine out by himself.
是的 但也可能不止两个
Yeah, but it could be more than two.
不 看一下弹壳分布
Nah. Look at the shell groupings.
其中一人在后面 解决了汤姆
One was back there. He hit Tom.
另一个人就从这边过来
The second one came this way.
然后杀害了四个警员
Then he murdered all four of us.
是的
Yeah.
第二个杀手很厉害
Second one's a talented killer.
你少说了一个零 混蛋
You left a zero off, motherfucker.
什么？
What?
那可不止30公斤
That wasn't 30 keys stepped on.
那可是300公斤纯的
It was 300 pure.
不能怪我
Wasn't my fuckup.
那怪谁
Whose fuckup was it?
怪霍克·泰勒吧 那家伙把活分包出去的
Hawk Tyler's, maybe? He put the job out for bid.
但你们也有货对吗？
But you guys got something, right?
-有50公斤  -好的
- Fifty keys. - Well, good.
-去你的  -交易得改改了
- Fuck you! - I'm changing the deal.
你不用替我们卖货了.
You're not selling it for us anymore.
你带我们去见霍克 我们把货直接卖给他.
You're gonna bring us to Hawk, and we're gonna sell it ourselves.
我们不需要第三方销货
And we're not splitting it three ways.
我欠了一屁股外债
I owe a lot of money to a lot of people...
我和雷下半辈子得跑路了！
Me and Ray have to run for the rest of our fucking lives!
霍克不会接受新交易的
Hawk ain't gonna hear new deals.
的确 可是霍克也不知道我们有50公斤高纯度的可卡因啊.
Yeah, well, Hawk hasn't heard 50 pure yet.
把电话给我.
Give me your phone.
发现目标
Hit.
我们发现目标了
We got a hit!
这是红灯摄像头拍到的
It's a red light cam.
两个人.
Two men.
通知大家 把照片发送给莫斯托的警方
Alert everybody. Send it through the mobile unit at Mosto's.
戴维斯警探.
Detective Davis.
我是约兰达·贝尔中士 身份识别中心的值班主管
Sergeant Yolanda Bell, shift supervisor at LMSI.
很高心认识你 约兰达·贝尔.
Good to know you, Yolanda Bell.
我们有东西给你.
We got something for you.
你想赌多少 我赌找到那辆宝马时已经烧得只剩底盘了
How much you wanna bet when we find that BMW, it's burnt to the chassis?
五分钱
A nickel.
如果你要抢劫660磅的可卡因.
If you were gonna rob 660 pounds of coke,
你会开一辆双门宝马轿车去抢劫吗？
would you drive a BMW two-door to the job?
只带一个同伙？
Would you bring just one other guy with you?
还只抢50公斤？
Would you only take 50 keys?
都不可能
No, no, and no.
他们没想到会有300公斤
They weren't expecting 300.
他们也没有想到会有警察
They weren't expecting cops, either.
要么是他们倒霉
This was either dumb luck...
要么是圈套
or a setup.
不 草泥马！
No, fuck you!
FBI来这是因为
The FBI's here because the shooters
凶手已经跑了
are out of the state by now.
离最后的枪声已经过去了半个小时了
Half hour since the final whistle.
请等我们再找到一个目击线索
Please, make one more sports analogy.
如果我们得到确认
If and when we get confirmation
凶手已经跑到新泽西或者康乃狄克州...
that they crossed over to cor Connecticut...
市长比较倾向于FBI接手这个案子越快越好
The mayor would prefer that the FBI take over sooner than later.
市长一有机会就贬低我们
The mayor shits on us every chance he gets.
他都不算真正的纽约人
The fucking guy eats pizza with a fork.
他希望这些人被绳之以法
He wants them brought to justice.
放屁
No shit.
德烈
Dre.
特万
Toine.
内务局那边怎么样？
How'd it go with Internal Affairs?
我来这了 所以不是你希望的那样
I'm here, so not the way you hoped.
和我之前说的一样 市长想将他们绳之以法
Like I said, the mayor wants them brought to justice,
比如逮捕 提起诉讼 接受审判
i.e., arrested, arraigned, put on trial.
而不是乱枪击毙 细节就不多说了
Not killed in a gun battle, the details of which are foggy.
就像我们牺牲的那七位？
Like the seven behind us?
你是哪位？缉毒警
Who are you? Narcotics.
完美 简直一应俱全 一个是缉毒刑警 一个喜欢开枪
Beautiful. What could go wrong? We got a narc and a trigger.
你说话最好好听点 什么叫“喜欢开枪”
You better have perfect diction, calling me a "trigger."
所有人都别吵了
Cut the shit, everybody.
市长赞同这件事吗？
Has the mayor got his thumb on this?
这是请求还是命令？
This an ask or an order?
他们还在纽约
They're still in New York.
不会有人拿着50公斤九成纯度的可卡因跑路的
You don't walk away with 50 keys of 90% pure
除非他有当地的大客户
unless you have a big local buyer.
除非你有运输工具否则不会把毒品带远
You don't move it far unless you're into transport.
这些家伙是打手 不是司机
These guys were hitters, not drivers.
你并不能确定
You don't know that.
他们可以干掉七个警察
Good enough to kill seven cops,
却又蠢到去闯红灯吗？
dumb enough to run a red?
他们需要做的是卖掉可卡因 然后消失
What they need to do is sell the coke, vanish.
他们不会去东边
I'm not heading east.
往长岛方向跑
Long Island runs out,
全都是会计
and it's all accountants
和牙医
and dentists out that way,
如果我有那么多货
so I'm a sore thumb.
我是不会去皇后区的
I'm not going to Queens.
中产阶级是不会买那么多可卡因的
You don't wholesale coke in the middle class.
我也不会呆在布鲁克林这个不法之地
I'm not staying in Brooklyn, scene of the crime.
加上现在全是像你一样的便衣和巡警
Plus, it's all pop-ups and strollers and guys like you now.
斯塔滕岛上还有谁能这么快的运送毒品呢？
Anyone left on Staten Island who can move this kind of weight as quick as they need?
在黑帮大佬戈蒂杀了卡斯特拉诺之后就没有人了
Not since the days before Gotti murdered Castellano.
新泽西州呢？
What about Jersey?
《黑道家族》是个电视剧
"Sopranos" was a TV show.
上城区呢？ 那是扯淡
And upstate? That's fucking ridiculous.
没有办法能在尤蒂卡运送50公斤毒品
Ain't no way to move 50 keys of yayo in Utica.
只剩下曼哈顿了
Leaves Manhattan.
戴维斯警探
Detective Davis?
怎么了 找到线索了吗
What, you got a hit for me?
收到报警电话
911 call.
有辆黑色双门宝马
Black BMW, two-door,
在中国城被烧了
on fire in an alley in Chinatown.
哦 哪个中国城？
Uh-oh, where's Chinatown?
曼哈顿的
Manhattan.
-感觉不错？ -确实
- Feel good? - It does.
-多久以前的来电？ -一分半以前
- How long ago was the 911? - Ninety seconds.
-我们走  -等一下
- Let's go. - Wait, wait, wait.
-还等什么  -关于他们的信息
- For what? - Everything about these guys,
除了测速摄像以外 我们知道的太少了
save the speed camera, has been competent so far.
所以呢？他们会卖了可卡因 接着赶火车
Yeah, so? They'll sell the coke, catch a train,
搭出租 抢辆车
catch a cab, jack a car,
我们还在这里希望能通过摄像头找到他们
and we're right back to hoping we get a hit from a cam
在他们消失并出现在宾夕法尼亚州之前
before they vanish, show up in Pennsylvania somewhere.
有道理  不过FBI是全国...
Good point. Whereas the FBI is national...
封锁这个岛
Close the island.
哪个岛？
What island?
曼哈顿岛
Manhattan.
你疯了吗？
You having a seizure?
不 市长会同意的
No, the mayor will buy it.
他现在才30多岁 犯罪率在上升
He's in the low 30s, crime is ticking up,
无家可归的人在蒂芙尼店门口撒尿
homeless are pissing in front of Tiffany's again,
现在是凌晨一点 不是下午一点
and it's 1:00 a.m., not 1:00 p.m.
如果出现意外 我们背锅
Anything goes wrong, you can blame us.
如果出事你们就惨了
Something will go wrong, and then you're all fucked.
我们知道FBI不懂牺牲就像不懂量子力学一样
We get the concept of sacrifice is like quantum physics to a fucking fed.
市长可以说是他听从了实战指挥官的意见
The mayor can say he was listening to his commanders in the field.
现在 如果你们上司有机会
Now, if your boss had a chance
能抓住杀了七个纽约警察的凶手
to catch the murderers of seven New York City cops
但不去做 这个城市不会原谅他的
and chose not to, this city would never forgive him.
5点之前抓住他们
Catch them by 5:00.
等一下 你们这是同意了吗？
Wait, is that a yes or a no?
5点之前抓住他们
Catch them by 5:00.
你们都有胆量
You all got balls,
但是差点头脑
not a lot of brains.
祝你们好运
Good luck to you.
我们会等你们电话的
We'll be awaiting your phone call.
嗯 屏息以待吧
Yeah, hold your breath.
你打算怎么做？
How you gonna do this?
曼哈顿有21座桥 全部封锁
There are 21 bridges in and out of Manhattan. Shut them down.
三条河 全部关闭  四条隧道 全部堵住
Three rivers, close them. Four tunnels, block them.
把所有出岛的火车都拦住 特拉克 PATH 新泽西运输公司
Stop every train that leaves the island. Amtrak, PATH, New Jersey Transit,
长岛铁路 北地铁 还有环线地铁
LIRR, Metro-North, and loop the subways.
然后...
Then...
我们全岛展开搜索
we flood the island with blue.
如果有人想弃车 就要先开出五条街以外去 别扔在曼哈顿
You wanna ditch a car, you drive five blocks, not to Manhattan.
两组轮胎印
Two sets of tire tracks.
这里有场碰面
This was a meet-and-greet.
约兰达女士
Miss Yolanda.
嘿 我需要所有在宝马之后进入巷子的车的照片
Hey, I need pictures of every car that went into the alley after the BMW.
入口处没有摄像头
There aren't any cameras aimed right at the entrances.
巷子深处是按摩店和中餐馆
Alley backs up into massage parlors and Chinese restaurants.
是非法劳工 只要一安上摄像头 就会被毁坏
It's illegal workers. Every time a camera goes up, it gets pulled back down.
你能找出开过巷子两侧的所有车吗
Can you pick up every passing vehicle on either end?
什么时间段？
What interval?
从宝马进入巷子之后
From the time the BMW went into the alley
到有人报警发现火情的时候
to the first fire call to 911.
好的 稍等
Will do. Stand by.
你是他们说的那个人吗？
Are you who they say you are?
他们说我是谁？
Who do they say I am?
你来告诉我
You tell me.
你过去十年杀了好多人
You killed a lot of perps in the last ten years.
都是自卫才杀的
Never shot first.
从没主动杀过人？
Never?
好吧 让我说更具体一些 伯恩斯警官
All right, let me be more precise, Detective Burns.
没有正当理由我是不会开枪的
I've never fired without just cause.
为七个警察报仇感觉就是正当理由
Seven dead cops feels like a lot of just cause.
他们是杀手
These guys are killers.
我要确保今天晚上我们能互相照应
So I need to know that we got each other's backs tonight.
我家里还有个孩子
'Cause I got a kid at home.
她醒来不能没有母亲
Doesn't need to wake up without her mother.
你也是警察 我会照应你的
You wear that badge, I got your back.
请讲
Talk to me.
好的
All right.
我们去哪？ 上城区
Where we going? Uptown.
...已经封锁曼哈顿了
...has closed all access into and out of Manhattan.
在市政厅的声明中 市长办公室只能
In a statement from city hall, the mayor's office was only able to offer
对两名嫌疑犯作模糊的描述
a vague description of the two suspects.
他们告知两人都是男性 一白一黑
They tell us both are men. One is white, one is black.
他们携带武器 十分危险
They are known to be armed and extremely dangerous.
副市长安东尼·摩特支持封锁曼哈顿
Deputy Mayor Antoine Mott defends the decision to lock down the city.
他的原话是 “这两名歹徒已无路可逃
His statement says, "With no way off the island for these two fugitives,
现已出动纽约全部警力……
the NYPD has every available...
-是好货  -全力搜索曼哈顿”
- Nice. - ...officer scouring Manhattan."
你们有多少？
How much have you got?
五十公斤
Fifty kilos.
...直到成功完成这次搜索
..."until this manhunt is successfully completed."
-你好 兄弟  -你好
- What up, B? - What up?
这事太不寻常了
This ain't usual and customary.
今晚没有事情寻常
Nothing is tonight, man.
这是雷·杰克逊
This is Ray Jackson.
这是迈克尔...
And this is Michael...
你出的价是30公斤的
The bid you put out was for 30 keys.
实际却是300公斤
We walked in on 300.
难免有突发情况  对么
Sometimes lightning strikes, right?
你完全置身事外简直再好不过了
And even better when you're a borough away from it.
是的 的确如此
Yeah, most definitely.
听着  我们杀了警察  一辈子都要逃亡
Look, we killed cops, and now we gotta run forever.
那就带着你的讨价还价  滚上你的逃亡之旅吧  还有要说的么？
Then get on with your negotiations and fuck your little guilt trip, word?
我是个抢竞争对手货的毒贩
I'm a drug dealer who hit a rival drug dealer,
而你们就是给我干脏活的人
and you're the guns I got to do it.
你们认为我耍了你们  就因为有人少说了一个零？
You think I fucked you because someone somewhere forgot a zero?
我们不跟那些斤斤计较的混蛋交易
Our business doesn't attract a lot of detail-oriented motherfuckers.
你看不惯  自己干
You don't like it, make your own moves.
要么打车走人  要么咱们成交
Or go drive an Uber. Either way, let's make this deal
这样我就能以最快的速度
so I can get you America's Most Wanted motherfuckers
把你们两个头号通缉犯从我的住所赶出去
out of my crib fast as I can.
100万
One million.
比索？
Pesos?
呦！我就喜欢有货还不懂行情的傻瓜
Yo! I love it when fools strike gold but don't know the market price.
50公斤分200份
Fifty keys cuts into 200.
曼哈顿每份市场价是3万2
Going rate for a cut key in Manhattan is 32 G's.
也就是说给我们100万后
That means after a million to us,
你还剩540万
that's still 5.4 million for you.
他就是那些斤斤计较的混蛋之一
He's one of those detail-oriented motherfuckers.
警察！别动！搜查令！
Police! Don't move! Search warrant!
左边！
To the left!
警察！举起手来！
Police! Show me your hands!
转过来！
Turn around!
嘿  干什么！
Hey, come on.
怎么了？
What's going on?
放开他！不！他什么都没做！
Get off of him! No, he didn't do anything!
他不能呼吸了！
He can't breathe!
你要是把他杀了
You know if you kill him,
他就什么都不能告诉我们了
he can't tell us anything?
-站起来 过来  -好的
- Stand up. Step over here. - Okay.
怎么了？这是你的车吗？
What's going on? Is this you?
-不 这不是我的车  -可它登记在你名下
- No, that is not my car. - It's registered in your name.
是我前男友的 他的信用不好  所以登记在了我名下
My ex-boyfriend, he had terrible credit, so I put it in my name.
他说他把车卖了！
He said he sold it!
-他说谎  -他一直都说谎
- He lied. - All the time.
你打错人了！
You beat up the wrong man!
他不会有事
He'll live.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
我们走
Let's go.
嘿  你还好吗？
Hey. You okay?
转过来
Turn around.
奥  天
Oh, God.
够了 住手
Knock it off. Knock it off.
没关系 没关系
It's all right. It's all right.
所以 你的前男友...
So, this ex-boyfriend of yours...
托里亚诺·布什
Toriano Bush.
-他犯了什么事  -今晚死了7个警察
- What'd he do now? - Seven cops were murdered tonight.
-啊 不是托里亚诺做的  -他安排了这两个人
- Well, Toriano didn't do that. - He picked up these two men.
我们认为他们是凶手
We think they're the murderers.
这两个人迄今还没找到
There isn't a version of this where these two aren't found.
现在请你配合
Cooperate now.
告诉我一些我不知道的事情
Tell me something I don't know,
说完我们立马离开
and that's the beginning of the end of our time together.
你知道吗  托里亚诺是不会杀人的
Toriano couldn't kill anyone, you know?
你说过了 但他犯过罪 是吗
You said that. But he's a criminal, right?
一些小罪 想赚钱脱身 他总是深陷债务
Small-time. Wanted to get out. He was always just too deep in debt.
所以你离开了他？
Is that why you left him?
我不是因为债务离开的
Debt don't bother me.
那勾引他的小三是谁
Who was Becky with the good hair?
她是泛美酒吧的服务员
This waitress ho at the Pan-Am.
-去查查  -谢谢
- Check it. - Thank you.
坐
Sit.
你回避一下
Give us a sec.
嘿 约兰达 把托里亚诺·布什的所有信息都给我
Hey, Yolanda, get me everything you have on Toriano Bush.
调一下泛美酒吧附近的监控
And get cameras up and around the Pan-Am Lounge.
他女朋友在那里
He has a girlfriend there.
收到
Got it.
每捆一百张？
You have it in hundreds?
你们花美元
Brown people spend Benjamins,
会被追踪
brown people get followed.
与可卡因一样重
Weighs as much as the coke.
你说的对
You about right.
一百万在20年代相当于110英镑
A million in 20s is 110 pounds.
还有 离警犬远点儿
And stay away from all canines.
缉毒犬能闻到钞票上沾有可卡因的气味
They go Cujo because every dollar in circulation is covered in cocaine atoms,
并且  你们那6个小包中总共有5万钞票
and y'all got 50,000 of those bills in six small bags.
-那我怎么洗钱  -你没有认识的脱衣舞俱乐部老板
- How do I clean it? - You don't know some dude who owns a strip club
-或者经营停车场的?  -这是7位数
- or a parking lot? - This is seven figures.
你用谁？
Who do you use?
有7位或者更多的其他人
Who everybody else with seven or more digits does.
在肉库区有个叫阿迪的苏丹兄弟
Sudanese brother over in the Meatpacking named Adi.
也是警察  瑞士人
Cops, too. He's Switzerland.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是他要拿30万
Means he's gonna take 300,000,
但他能提供银行账户 护照 你需要的一切
but he can sort bank accounts, passports, whatever you need.
我听过这个人 很孤傲
I heard about this dude. Exclusive.
他欠你钱？
He owe you money?
布什欠所有人钱
Bush owes everybody money.
是吗？多少？
Yeah? How much?
到今早是17512美元
$17,512, as of this morning.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我刚买了你的车
I just bought your Lincoln.
我们走
Let's get out of here.
他们永远不会知道的
They'll never know.
你再也不会看到我
You'll never see me again.
我保证
I promise.
好吧  他...
Yeah, that's...
可能是雷蒙德·杰克逊
probably Raymond Jackson.
“可能？”
"Probably"?
他一直戴着恶魔面具 你能认出？
Because he always wears a demon mask?
世界大战爆发的时候 很少有白人生长在这里
Not many white dudes born and raised where we were during World War Crack.
好吧
Okay.
所以 他是个硬汉
So he's a tough guy.
是的  他一生都在战斗
Yeah, fighting his whole life.
我们还是孩子时
When we were kids,
我见过他打一个成年人
I watched him beat a grown man
因为那个人踩了阿维尔的球鞋
for stepping on this boy Arvell's sneakers.
这是入伍前的事了
This was before the army.
阿维尔？
Arvell?
阿维尔是谁？
Who's Arvell?
阿维尔·特鲁希略
Arvell Trujillo.
他和雷一起入的伍
He and Ray, they joined up together.
他们什么都一起做
They just did everything together.
他是车里的另一个人吗？
Is that who else is in the car?
不是
No.
阿维尔在阿富汗被炸死了
Arvell was blown up in Afghanistan.
车里的另一个人...
The other man in that car...
可能是阿维尔的弟弟  迈克尔
is probably Arvell's little brother, Michael.
因为雷现在罩着他
Because Ray protects him now.
你知道吗？迈克尔很聪明
Michael's smart, you know?
如果他生在别处
He could have been anything
他可能会出人头地的
if he'd have just been born somewhere else.
但在阿维尔死后
But after Arvell was killed,
迈克尔也参军了
Michael joined up.
但我听说他袭击了一名军官
But I heard he attacked a sergeant.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
-进来  -我们收到报告
- Come on in. - We are getting reports
出站口  大桥  还有隧道交通拥堵
of huge traffic jams at the outbound entrances, bridges, and tunnels.
今晚没有人能离开这座岛
No one is getting off this island tonight.
你们引起了一场骚动
You're causing quite a stir.
..今晚在布鲁克林通缉杀害七名警察的凶手
...wanted for the slaughter of seven officers
雷蒙德·杰克逊和迈克尔·特鲁希略
in Brooklyn tonight are Raymond Jackson and Michael Trujillo.
杰克逊  32岁  有长期暴力犯罪记录
Jackson, at 32 years old, a long history of violent crime.
特鲁希略  26岁  同样拥有大量犯罪前科
Trujillo, 26 years old, also with an extensive rap sheet.
二人都曾在军队服役...
Both men are ex-military...
包放这儿
Put your bags in here.
特鲁希略因不光彩原因被开除军籍
Trujillo was dishonorably discharged.
该死
Fuck.
刚刚收到一则纽约警局传来的消息
We're just getting a statement from the NYPD, just issued.
受伤警察 詹妮弗·蒙哥马利
We have been told that the injured officer, Jennifer Montgomery,
在几分钟前抢救无效 宣布殉职
was taken off life support and declared dead just minutes ago.
不数数吗？
Don't wanna count it?
钱在我所知之地 不怕你骗
No one cheats the man who knows where all their money is.
不准关保险柜
Do not close that fucking safe.
你在干嘛
What the fuck are you doing?
-我不相信  -不相信什么
- I don't buy it. - Buy what?
这个家伙  还有这个地方
This guy, this place.
我们在哪 迈克
Where the fuck are we, Mike?
我们在干什么  我们不该这样
What are we doing? This isn't us.
我们有一百万现金
We have a million in fucking cash.
我们难得能见到这么多钱
You ever think we'd see that?
你觉得阿维尔没有梦到过这么多钞票吗
You ever think Arvell even dreamed of this shit?
现在我们就这么拱手给他？  然后呢
Now we're just gonna give it to him? Then what?
他把钱放进保险柜 锁上
He's gonna put it in the fucking safe, type,
然后拿几张礼品券把我们打发掉？
and give us some fucking gift cards?
-就这样是吗  -布什了解这个人
- It's that easy? - Bush knew about this dude.
“很孤傲”  还记得吗  布什知道他的
"Exclusive," remember? Bush heard about him.
托利亚诺就是罪魁祸首
Fucking Toriano's how all this started.
不  我们不赶紧逃命才会祸生事端
No, us not walking away is how this started.
听着 雷 今晚这一切都说不通
Look, Ray, I get it. None of this shit makes any sense.
我们从来没遇到过这种事
It ain't like anything we've ever known.
我们已无路可退
But ain't no plan B I can see.
他们封锁了整个岛
They shut down the island.
我们无法带着这么一大笔不干净的钞票跑路
We can't run around with 100 pounds of stained cash.
他把钱存在远离这里的其他账户里
He puts this money in some accounts somewhere far from here,
之后我们再想办法拿到钱就行了
and then we figure out how to get to it later.
雷 把枪放下
Ray, put it down.
你要是敢耍我们
You fuck us,
不管你在天涯海角 我都不会放过你
and I will fucking bury you where you stand.
我得喝点酒
I need a fucking scotch.
行 我给我们一人倒一杯
I'll pour us both one.
匹配到了
We got a match.
我们找到了
We got a hit.
布什在俱乐部
Bush is at the club.
已查到托利亚诺·布什在泛美酒吧
Positive ID on Toriano Bush at the Pan-Am.
离得最近的小组注意 前往泛美酒吧
Closest units, converge on the Pan-Am Lounge.
托利亚诺·布什在里面
Toriano Bush inside.
堵住出口
Stay on the exits.
我到之前  任何人不准进入
Nobody enters until I get there.
不  不  听我说  宝贝
No, no! Listen to me, baby.
警察 放下武器
Police! Drop it!
-布什！  -给我往后退
- Bush! - Get the fuck back!
-嘿  叫你往后退  -我是救护员
- Hey, get the fuck back! - I'm an EMT.
我管你是谁  给我后退
I don't give a shit! Get the fuck back!
让开  都给我让开
Out of the way. Get out of the way!
小心小心
Watch it, watch it, watch it.
让开 让开
Move, move, move!
快呀 安德烈 快接电话
Come on, Andre. Answer your fucking phone.
这是怎么回事
What the fuck is this?
嘿！
Hey!
-我不是叫你们等着吗  -我们没等
- Didn't I say wait? - We disobeyed.
-没等？  -他杀的不是你的兄弟
- You disobeyed? - He didn't kill one of your brothers.
你觉得我会放过他吗
So fuck if I'm gonna let him get away with...
你怎么能这么蠢  他谁也没杀
What are you, fucking stupid? He didn't kill anybody!
本来我们可以靠他找到那两个杀人凶手
He could have led us to the two who did!
我们喊他 他掏枪 我们就开枪了
We yelled. He pulled. We shot.
事情就这样 一死两逃
End of story. One down, two to go.
你在胡说八道
That's fucking bullshit!
都说了这个人渣是那两个
Says the side piece of a man who helped
警察杀手的帮凶
fucking cop killers!
你今晚喝了多少
How many drinks you have tonight?
嘿  你最好别这样
Hey, don't do what you're doing right now.
别碰老子
Get your fucking hands off me.
不！
No!
怎样 怎样
What? What?
长官 把他们赶出去 我们走
Officer, get them the fuck out of here. Let's go.
你说布什掏枪
You said Bush pulled.
掏的什么枪
Pulled what?
38式手枪？
A fucking .38?
在逃的两个人都带着管制轻型冲锋枪
The other two got suppressed submachine guns,
布什就只带着这么一把小玩意儿？
and Bush was carrying a piece you only ever see in a meth addict's glove box...
就跟某位胖警察脚踝上带的一样
or a fat cop's ankle holster.
嘿  哇哦
Hey, whoa, whoa.
谁打来的 身份信息中心吗
Who was that, LMSI?
是我家的保姆  不好意思  我小女儿她…
Nanny. Sorry. My little girl's...
没什么事吧
Is everything all right?
没事 没啥大问题
No, but we'll be fine.
这里出什么事了
What the fuck is going on here?
我正在调查
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
你的肤色正好适合去巴哈马群岛
Bahamas is right for your skin color.
要经过迈阿密
You'll go via Miami.
32万6太少了
Three hundred twenty-six is short.
剩余的是现金
The rest is cash.
你现在是克里斯托弗·詹姆士
You are now Christopher James.
雷 你的新名字是威廉姆·辛普森
And, Ray, your new name is William Simpson.
你们得分开坐车去迈阿密
Take separate buses to Miami.
在哈瓦那有个叫斯威夫特的人
There's a man named Swift in Little Havana.
他在弗拉格勒的27号街开了个酒吧
He runs a bar at the corner of Flagler and 27th Street.
他还卖护照 你们找他办新的护照
He also sells passports. They'll be under your new names.
然后用现金包一辆船去拿索
Then you will pay cash for a charter boat to Nassau.
那扇门后面有一个滑雪靴的包和一个双肩包
There is a ski boot bag and backpack behind that door.
我会各放15万在里面
I'll put 15 in each...
什么情况
What was that?
就是听到的那样
It's exactly what it sounds like.
门后那位 你别轻举妄动
Whoever is at my door, you wait and you think.
纽约市警察局  把门打开
NYPD! Open up!
告诉我你们是哪个辖区的
What precinct are you from?
因为我要把你们…
Because I'll have your fucking...
进去
Going in!
靠
Fuck!
看看你俩干的好事
You two better not have fucked up.
没什么事吧
Are we good?
这是我的案子吧  队长
Is this my case, Captain?
大家各司其职 不过你是领队
This is all hands on deck, but you're lead.
他们早该知道的
Someone should tell them.
听着 他们在气头上
Look, they're angry.
也很痛苦
They're in pain.
布奇科夫妇和詹妮弗·蒙哥马利是好朋友
Butchco and his wife were close with Jennifer Montgomery.
她没能挺过来 他们对此难以平复
She didn't make it. They just pulled the plug.
10-13队  我们需要支援
10-13, we need backup!
我是凯利
This is Kelly!
我们在十三号街九号  双方交火  10-13队
We're on Ninth and 13th, shots fired! 10-13!
十三号街九号 嫌疑人特鲁希略和杰克逊在这里
Ninth and 13th! Suspects Trujillo and Jackson here!
凯利怎么找到他们的
How the fuck did Kelly find them?
我什么都看不见了
I can't see anything.
我瞎了
I can't fucking see.
我发誓 兄弟 我们什么都没做
We didn't fuck you over, man. I swear.
混蛋  你们最好自行了断
Put those guns in your mouths, you motherfuckers!
该死的8-5警员
Fucking 8-5.
什么？
What?
把枪放下
Throw your guns down,
王八蛋
you motherfuckers!
他的拇指驱动器
It's his thumb drives.
那个驱动器
The thumb drives!
这是什么
What is it?
-密码“Coolhand”   -什么？
- "Coolhand." - Huh?
密码”Coolhand”  无空格 全拼小写
"Coolhand," one word, lowercase.
把枪放下  赶紧投降
Get the shotgun. Get the shotgun!
我们得走了
We gotta fucking move.
全体注意  嫌疑人徒步逃走了
All units, suspects are 90Z on foot!
-在这 不要呼叫  -十三号街九号附近
- Right there. Don't call it in. - Vicinity of Ninth and 13th.
我们去抓
They're ours.
我们得分头行动
We gotta split up.
一起行动容易被抓到
We're too easy to track if we're together.
不行 你一个人不行
No. No way, man. You need help.
自己小心 见机行事
Head down, eyes up.
我们迈阿密见
I'll see you in Miami.
滚
Go!
好的
Okay.
他没我那么坏
He ain't like me.
迈克
Mike.
他没我那么坏
He ain't like me.
雷死了吗
Is Ray dead?
希望如此
I hope so.
迈克尔
Michael?
雷死了吗
Is he dead?
没错
Yes.
别过来
Stop walking.
你只管开枪
You got a clear shot. Take it.
不用管我
Don't worry about me.
你可真走运
You got lucky.
是啊
Yeah.
比他刚刚杀害的平民幸运多了
Luckier than the civilian he just murdered.
会把他算进受害警察名单里
Add that to the list of cops.
雷已经死了 你还想制造多少尸体
How many bodies stacked up against you now that Ray is dead?
-别想说服我  -简单的事实 迈克尔
- Don't try and get into my head, okay? - Simple truths, Michael.
别叫我的名字
And don't use my name!
开枪！
Take the shot!
别往前走了！
Stop fucking walking!
我觉得大部分责任都是雷的
I think most of this mess is his.
但你现在深陷泥沼了 迈克尔
But you're balls-deep in it now, Michael.
对于像雷这样的人 我生来便与之为敌
For guys like Ray, I'm natural causes.
但你呢？
But what about you?
你怎么知道雷是什么样的人呢？
Fuck you know about guys like Ray, huh?
你又怎么了解我这种人？
Fuck you know about guys like me?
看过你的档案
Saw your records.
在你哥哥死后试图追随他 加入海军
Marine. Tried to follow in your brother's footsteps after he got sent home in a box.
但你不光彩的被遣散
But you... dishonorably discharged.
因为抗命
Insubordination.
我理解
I get it.
我们中的某些人是杀人犯 迈克尔
Some of us are killers, Michael.
但你 我相信你是最不愿意杀害无辜的人
But you, I think the last thing you want is to take a life for no reason.
你怎么知道的？
And how you know that, huh?
因为你本可以现在就杀了她
Because you would have killed her by now.
开枪
Shoot him!
-不  -快开枪！
- No! - Fucking shoot him!
迈克尔 你想聊聊
Michael wants to talk.
那我们就聊聊 迈克尔
So, come on, Michael. Let's talk.
他要想聊 就让他别用枪指着我的头 安德烈
He wants to talk, tell him to do it without a gun to my fucking head, Andre.
伯恩斯 冷静点
Burns, be cool.
我现在很冷静
This is fucking cool.
就给我一点时间
Just give me a second here.
没有一件事可以说得通
None of this shit makes any sense.
我们打伤的那个经理 他知道警察会来
The manager at the spot we hit, he knew the cops were coming.
那是无声警报
It's called a silent alarm.
不是  他在这些发生之前看了一次表
No. He checked his watch before it all happened.
一开始来的四个人都悄无声息
And the first four came peacefully.
我的意思是 他们敲门都敲得彬彬有礼
I mean, one fucking knocked with his knuckles like a Jehovah's Witness,
不像警察那样大力撞门
not with the side of his hand like a fucking cop.
安德烈 看在上帝的份上 你真的要听这些狗屁吗？
Andre, for the love of Christ, are you really gonna entertain this shit?
300公斤 纯的
Three hundred keys, pure.
我整个人都懵逼了
I mean, what the fuck?
这整件事情有蹊跷
This whole thing is filthy.
没人能神不知鬼不觉的运走这么大批货
You can't move that type of weight around without cartels or cops or both.
而且警察还打死了楼上的干洗店老板
And the cops shot the Cleaner upstairs,
直接从猫眼开枪 没有任何警告
fired right through the peephole, no warning.
他们来不仅仅为了抓我们
They were there for more than just us.
在我们离开之前 干洗店老板给了我拇指驱动器
And right before we left, the Cleaner gave me thumb drives.
给了什么？
Gave what?
驱动器
Drives.
像优盘一样东西
USBs and shit.
-里面有什么？  - 安德烈
- What's on them? - Andre.
他只说了“8-5”
All he said was "8-5."
你个杀警察的人渣
Cop-killing piece of shit!
-根本没有...  -伯恩斯 停！停下！
- There's no fucking... - Burns, stop! Stop!
迈克尔 看着我
Michael, look at me.
-别耍花招  -没人耍花招
- Don't fuck with me! - Nobody's fucking with you.
但事实是 你打死了她 我会同时杀了你
But facts: You shoot her, I'm gonna kill you in the same breath.
那你所知道的一切就都化为乌有了
And everything you think you know or may have means nothing.
所以放下枪 我们一起看看驱动器里都有什么
So drop your weapon, and let's take a look at the drives.
不  不  我做不到
No. No, I can't do that.
-迈克尔 你需要相信我   -我不信任何人
- Michael, I need you to trust me. - I don't trust anybody!
你没有选择了
You have no choice.
即使开放城市 你也是插翅难逃
You're not gonna escape to some island somewhere, even after they open this one.
你那么聪明应该明白这点
You're smart enough to know that.
我 嗯？
I am, huh?
这世界你已经无处可藏了
The world's just gonna keep closing in on you.
但只要你束手就擒 就能挺过这一劫
But you can survive this if you just give yourself up to me.
不！迈克尔！
No! Michael!
不！
No!
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
你在做什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
我是戴维斯
This is Davis.
封锁七个街区的范围
Lock down everything in a seven-block radius
就以维切尔牛肉店为中心
from Weichsel Beef's center of the circle.
我确认迈克尔·特鲁希略90秒前从这离开
Positive ID on Michael Trujillo leaving there 90 seconds ago.
特鲁希略有对此案至关重要的信息
Trujillo has information vital to this case.
只许活捉
He must be brought in alive.
-让我看看  -我没事
- Let me see. - I'm fine.
好 你当心
Yeah, you look it.
我想知道那驱动器里都有什么
I wanna know what's on those drives.
控制中心 通知84号单位建立防线
Central, advise the units that are 84 to set up a perimeter
从西12街到西19街 从第八大道到水边
from West 12th Street to West 19th and from Eighth Avenue to the water.
不准任何人进出
No one in or out.
什么？你能相信吗？
What? Can you believe that?
恶心 很恶心
Disgusting. It's disgusting.
游泳池在26楼
And the pool is on the 26th floor.
嘘
Shh!
你不出声 我就不会伤害你
I won't hurt you if you stay quiet.
知道了吗
You got it?
知道就点头
Nod.
该死
Shit. Fuck.
电脑密码是什么
What's the password?
呃
Um...
Eightclap1
"Eightclap1."
你需要把“eight”拼写出来
Gotta spell the word "eight."
1是数字
One is the number.
没空格？嗯
One word? Mm-hmm.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
你为什么没开枪？
Why didn't you shoot him?
他们告诉我你无所畏惧
They told me you were fearless.
说你是手刃警察杀手的人
The guy who kills cop killers.
我就是想知道真相 就这样
I just need the truth, that's all.
你相信一个警察杀手的话？
You believe a cop killer?
做得好 凯利  休息一下
Good work, Kelly. Get some rest.
你干掉了一个恶棍
You took down one vicious son of a bitch.
是的 可惜没在他杀害无辜平民之前
Yeah, not before he killed an innocent civilian.
你为世界铲除了一颗老鼠屎
World's a better place with that guy gone.
你看过他的档案吗？
You seen his record?
瞄了一眼
Glanced at it.
我就知道找你负责是对的
I knew I had the right guy for this.
各司其职 不是吗
All hands on deck, right?
是你们的人把他们从公寓里赶出来的
It was your boys who smoked them out of this apartment.
凯利警官怎么这么快就找到这了？
How did Lieutenant Kelly even get here so quick?
看看这乱的
Look at this fucking mess.
-仍然有一个在逃的 对吗？  -是的
- You still got one guy on the run, right? - Yeah.
已经早上4:37了
It's 4:37 a.m.
在我开放曼哈顿之前 你只有不到一个小时了
You've got less than an hour before I gotta open the island.
如果你那时还没抓到他 可就回天乏术了
You haven't gotten him by then, we're all eating shit for breakfast.
不要担心那个在逃犯
Don't worry about the other perp.
安德烈已经把他封锁在七个街区的范围内了
Andre put that motherfucker in a seven-block box.
他快超过时限了
He's on borrowed time.
迈克尔·特鲁希略仍不知所踪
Michael Trujillo is still at large,
但警方认为他被困在肉库区的某个地方
but police believe he is surrounded somewhere inside the Meatpacking District.
市长办公室表扬了纽约警察局官员
The mayor's office has praised NYPD officers
感谢他们在追捕过程中取得的进展
for the progress they've made in this manhunt.
副市长安东尼·摩特
Deputy Mayor Antoine Mott had this to say
在刚才的新闻发布会上说
in a press briefing just moments ago.
德拉姆市长缩短了他对欧盟的贸易访问
Mayor Drum cut short his trade mission to the EU
他已经在从布鲁塞尔回国的飞机上了
and is already on a plane home from Brussels.
请我转达他对本市市民的谢意
Asked me to pass along his gratitude to the citizens of this city.
他说 “纽约市民是世界上最棒的”
"World's greatest," his words.
没有你们的耐心和帮助
Without your patience and assistance,
我还要补充一点 德拉姆市长大胆的想法
and, I'll add, the boldness of Mayor Drum's idea
先封锁曼哈顿
to close Manhattan in the first place,
不然我们也不可能在莫斯托的埋伏中
we wouldn't have already neutralized two of the three men responsible
干掉那三个人中的两个
for the ambush at Mosto's
他们昨晚害我们第85区分局的
that claimed the lives of eight of our finest
八名优秀警员殉职
from the 85th Precinct last night.
一名枪手已确认是雷蒙德·杰克逊
A gunman identified as Raymond Jackson
他的同伙 托里亚诺·布什
and his accomplice, Toriano Bush,
两人都于今天凌晨在拒捕中被击毙
both died resisting arrest in the early hours of this morning.
两个人都有武器 很危险
Both men were armed and dangerous.
我们英勇的警员在第85分局...
Our brave officers at the 85th Precinct...
Eighty-fifth.
“8-5”
"Eight-five."
我们相信还有第三个同伙
We believe we have the third man,
迈克尔·特鲁希略 他已插翅难逃
Michael Trujillo, within our grasp.
Eighty-five.
我们要求所有居民就地避难
We ask all residents to shelter in place
我们会逮捕特鲁希略 让他为自己的罪行负责
while we apprehend Trujillo and hold him accountable for his crimes.
警察编号
Badge numbers.
每个编号代表一个警察
Every number's a cop.
救命！ 救命！救命！
Help! Help! Help!
我找安保部总监 他在吗?
Could I speak to the director of security, please?
抱歉 先生 稍等
I'm sorry, Officer, just one moment.
前台
Reception.
什么？
What?
先生 你不能来这儿
Sir, you can't be back here.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我们得活捉他
We gotta bring him in alive.
在视觉酒店发生了一场袭击 听起来是特鲁希略做的
...assault at the Parallax Hotel. Sounds like Trujillo.
从后方的厨房逃逸
Direction of flight was through the kitchen at rear.
那里是第十三大道 把他堵在那里
That's 13th Street. Lock him in.
不准其他人靠近 我来追
Nobody approach him! He's mine!
先生 站住
Sir, stop.
站住别动 举起双手
Hold it right there! Show me your hands!
快开车 从另一头截住他
Take the car! Cut him off on the other side!
不要开枪!
Don't shoot!
特鲁希略 放下武器
Trujillo! Drop your weapon!
这里是警察 停下 趴下
Police. Stop, drop on the ground.
不要开枪! 不要开枪!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
我是警察
Police.
我是警察 别动 别动 别动
Police, don't move, don't move, don't move.
把门口让开 把门口让开
Clear the doorway. Clear the doorway.
别挡着门
Clear the doorway.
纽约警局现在负责查案
NYPD. Take cover.
让开! 让开!
Clear! Clear!
赶紧让开!
Come on, clear!
警察 让开 让开
Police. Clear, clear.
别挡道 纽约警察办案
Out of the way. NYPD. Take cover.
快走 快走 快走
Move. Move. Move.
快离开 快离开 快离开
Clear. Clear. Clear.
放下武器
Drop it!
你是今天晚上第一个先讲话后开枪的警察
You're the only cop tonight who speaks first and shoots second.
现在已经是早上了 你杀了我们八个人
It's fucking morning, and you killed eight of us.
他们不全是好警察
Not all eight were clean.
谁关心这个?
Who cares?
你会
You do.
你怎么知道我跟别人不同?
How do you know I'm any different?
因为你到现在都没有向我开枪
Because you would have shot me by now.
之前说的驱动器在哪儿
Where are those drives we were talking about?
我藏起来了
I stashed them.
好的
Okay.
交给我 我会保你活着
Give them to me, and I'll keep you alive.
不
No.
你想要驱动器 那就放我走
You want the drives, you let me go.
如果你不和我一起走出去 你会被其他警察抓的
If you don't walk out with me, you'll be carried out by others.
迈克尔 你唯一的希望就是讲出真相
Michael, your only hope is to tell the truth,
向上帝请求原谅
pray to God for forgiveness,
你需要接受的事实是你可能会死在监狱里
and make peace with the fact that you may die in prison.
现在朝你开枪会是一个更好的选择
Shooting you sounds a whole lot better right now.
你不会想我的脸和这个脏乱地铁
You don't want my face and this dirty subway
是你最后看到的东西
to be the last things you ever see.
如果我死了 你永远也不会知道驱动器上的内容是什么
If I die, you'll never find out what's on those drives.
我也许找不到驱动器
I may not find the drives,
但我会找出今晚这些事情发生的原因
but I will find out why tonight happened.
但是你要怎么证明它?
But could you prove it?
我只需要向我自己证明就行了
I only have to prove it to myself.
放下吧 迈克尔
Come on, Michael.
放下吧
Come on.
来
Okay.
给我
不要开枪!
Cease fire!
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
你搞什么鬼
What the fuck, man?
他在投降 他已经放弃抵抗了
He was surrendering. He was giving himself up.
他要朝你开枪
He was gonna shoot you.
你没看到枪已经放下了吗?
You didn't see the gun down?
该死的 你没看到吗?
You didn't fucking see the gun down?
我以为他要开枪的
I thought he was gonna shoot.
控制中心 这里是案发现场 4-3警员 收到请回答
Central, this is homicide 4-3. Do you copy?
控制中心 收到请回答
Central, do you copy?
请注意 我们在第六节车厢发生交火
Be advised, we have shots fired on the 6 train
请赶紧到中央车站
coming into Grand Central.
嫌疑人已被击毙 嫌疑人已被击毙
Suspect is down. Suspect is down.
密码"Coolhand"
"Coolhand."
收到请回答
Do you copy?
控制中心?
Central?
"Coolhand"
"Coolhand."
控制中心 收到请回答
Central, do you copy?
控制中心?
Central?
控制中心 收到信息请回复
Central, advise if you receive my transmission.
靠
Shit.
他死了吗？
Is he gone?
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我认为这案子他们没找错人
I think they called the right man for the job.
嘿 你做得很好
Hey. Good job. You did great work.
就该这么做 做得好
Way to go. Well done.
祝贺你 警探
Congratulations, Detective.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
-了不起  -谢谢你们
- Amazing. - Thanks, guys.
嘿
Hey.
怎么了
What's up?
-我手机没电了  -哦
- This fucking thing is dead. - Oh.
可以借一下你的吗?
Can I borrow yours?
好 当然
Yeah, of course.
-我一会儿就还你  -好的
- I'll bring it right back. - Sure.
做得好 警探
Good work, Detective.
很棒 伯恩斯
Great job, Burns.
谢谢 凯利
Thanks, Kelly.
-手怎么样  -还行
- How's the hand? - Okay.
好的 女士
Okay. Yes, ma'am.
是语音信箱
Voice mail.
靠
Shit.
今晚真是漫长 你需要好好休息
It's been a long night. You get some rest.
是的 你也是
Yeah, you too.
赶快回家抱抱女儿
Go hug that daughter of yours.
曼哈顿于今早七点零五分重新开放
Manhattan reopened at 7:05 this morning
在昨晚八名警察遇害之后
after a night of carnage that saw eight police officers...
曼哈顿被封锁 禁止出入
...into and out of Manhattan were closed last night.
亲眼看到了这场成功的追捕
...personally oversee the successful conclusion of the manhunt...
纽约警察成功击毙嫌疑人
...flooded by the NYPD
这看起来像是一场武装袭击
in what looked and felt like a military invasion.
怎么了?
What's up?
该死的
Goddammit.
好的 冷静
Okay, all right, calm down.
到我这里来吧
Just come over to my place.
好的
Yeah.
我明白了
I understand.
我们会尽快解决的
We'll figure something out.
别急
Just...
我先挂电话了
I gotta go.
我有客人
I got a visitor.
把你的枪放下
Put your gun down here.
你在跟谁通电话?
Who was on the phone?
我老婆
My wife.
她是个护士
She's a nurse.
刚准备轮班
Shift just started.
这就是结婚后的生活
And that's the story of all married life.
你和莫斯托的老板是一伙的
Guy that owned Mosto's was your partner.
莫斯托是你的金库
Mosto's was your vault.
8-5警队是装甲安保部队 你们用警车在城里运送毒品
The 8-5 was armored security, moving drugs around the city in NYPD vehicles.
昨晚真是穿道袍都撞鬼
Last night was just fucking bad luck on every level.
你们的人去莫斯托搬运可卡因时 碰巧遇上去抢货的竞争者
A rival hits Mosto's at the same time your boys drop by to move a load of coke,
恰好他们训练有素 你的人敌不过阵亡了
run into men with training, die, badly.
那群训练有素的人逃走后 卖掉毒品去洗钱
Those men with training escape, sell the drugs and clean the money,
又碰巧跟你找的是同一家洗衣店
coincidentally with the same launderer you use.
你杀人灭口 试图掩盖一切
And you scorch earth trying to cover it all up.
你很厉害
You're really good.
还不够
Not good enough.
昨晚被杀的警察中有几个并没参与
Not all the cops killed last night were a part of it.
不管好与坏 他们昨天都是被你害死的
Clean or dirty, they're all dead 'cause of you.
所以你应该知道
So you know,
这并不是为了凯迪拉克和劳力士这些物质财富
this is not about Cadillacs and fucking Rolexes, material bullshit.
我不是 我那些兄弟也不是
Not for me. Not for most of my guys.
都是为了生活
It's about having a life.
我管理8-5警队的第一个月 我就参加了两个兄弟的葬礼
My first month running the 8-5, I went to two of my cops' funerals.
第一个以60英里的时速撞向了桥墩
First one went 60 miles an hour into a bridge abutment.
当时他体内酒精浓度为0.25
His blood alcohol was .25.
第二人也是喝酒喝死的
Second guy drank himself to death too.
肝硬化
Cirrhosis.
我有三个手下自己的房子被查封了
Three of my cops had their homes foreclosed on.
其他人也失去了公寓住所
Another guy lost his apartment.
因为可恶的房东将房租涨了一倍
Shitty landlord doubled the rent.
8-5警队的离婚率超过百分之七十
The divorce rate in the 8-5 was over 70%.
这一切是为了让我的警员能留住婚姻
This is about my cops staying married,
抚养孩子
raising their kids,
无需每天花四小时堵在路上
not having to spend four hours a day sitting in traffic,
在一个消费不起的城市里摸爬滚打
crawling to and from a city they can't afford to live in,
这个城市一点都不欢迎他们
a city that actively fucking dislikes them.
但是他们仍日日夜夜
But a city that they protect...
用生命守护着这座城市
with their lives every fucking day.
就是如此
That's what this is about.
我跟你讲 说金钱买不到幸福的人都是放狗屁
I'll tell you what, anybody tells you money can't buy happiness is full of shit.
8-5警队就是证明
And the 8-5 is proof.
弗兰基·伯恩斯就是证明
Frankie Burns is proof.
你把她安插进来就是为了监视我吗
Did you put her on this just to make sure I did your bidding?
我安插她是因为她和你一样优秀
I put her on this 'cause she might be as good as you.
而且她也失去了一切
And she's got everything to lose.
三个人谋杀了我的父亲
Three guys murdered my father.
他干掉了两人
He took two with him.
但是第三人
But the third,
他把我父亲打的面目全非 血肉模糊
he hit my dad so many times he broke every bone in his face.
所以我们不得不把棺材盖得死死的
That's why we had to have a closed casket.
那个人告诉法官
Guy told the judge...
他甚至不记得做过这些
he didn't even remember doing it.
可卡因和粉的的纯度太高
He was so jacked, so...
以致他丧失理智
so high on cocaine and angel dust.
毒品无时无刻不在
The drugs have always been there.
随时随地都有
And they always will be.
人们也会因此丧命
And people will always die because of them.
这些人命 警察不能背负这些人命
That blood, that blood cannot be on the badge.
可你的闪存盘也是来路不明
You can't prove where those flash drives came from.
没人能挡我财路
And nobody is gonna take the stand against me.
你若明知山有虎偏向虎山行 那你只能孤军奋战
So if you go down this road, Andre, you're on your own.
你的余生都不能活的安心
You'll be looking over your shoulder the rest of your life.
我明白
I know.
你也可以选择视而不见
Or you could just look the other way.
我宁愿直视魔鬼
I'd rather look the devil in the eye.
我打中你了？
I get you?
你知道还问
You wouldn't ask if you didn't know.
伤的很重 是不是
Hurts like a motherfucker, right?
我死不了
I'll live.
如果你束手就擒就能活下来
You can if you give yourself up.
这是你唯一的选择
It's the only choice available to you right now.
或许
Maybe.
别乱动
Don't do it.
他死了
He's gone.
结束了
It's over.
把你的枪放下
So put your gun down.
我要转身面向你 伯恩斯
I'm gonna turn around and face you, Burns.
不
No.
我要转身了
I'm gonna turn around.
驱动器在我这里
I have the drives.
我做了备份
I copied them.
内容已经发出去了
They're already out in the world.
你误入歧途了 伯恩斯
You're going down, Burns.
8-5警队每一个有污点的警察都步入歧途
Every dirty cop in the 8-5 is going down.
你杀了我 就能继续生活
You pull that trigger, you get life.
你可以陪你女儿一起成长
Your daughter doesn't need to grow up without her mother.
警徽也放下
Badge too.
新浪微博 @摆渡字幕组 发布
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
摆渡字幕组翻译/APP开发志愿者招募中 报名群:377256405